ANSAR ALI

Software Developer

+91 7889797950



bhatansar03@gmail.com



Srinagar, J&K, India



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ansar-ali-607513235



SUMMARY

Highly skilled and driven Software Developer with one year of experience building responsive web applications. Proven record of providing technical solutions to develop an exceptional user experience. Solution-oriented and problem solver building and maintaining Web Applications using HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT,REACT JS, C#, ASP .NET CORE MVC, Entity Framework, ADO .Net and Microsoft SQL Server.

EDUCATION

University of Kashmir

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science 2017 - 2022

SKILLS

- Javascript
- React Js
- C#
- ASP .Net Core MVC
- Entity Framework
- ADO .Net
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Rest APIs
- JSON
- Redux / React Hooks
- HTML5 / CSS3 / Bootstrap
- OOPS
- Git / GitHub

SOFT SKILLS

- Communication
- Time Management
- Problem Solving
- Teamwork
- Decision Making

LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu
- Hindi
- Kashmiri

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

Softstacks Technologies Pvt Ltd | September 2022 - November 2023

- Collaborated with a cross-functional team to develop and maintain responsive and user- friendly websites, ensuring optimal functionality across different devices and browsers.
- Supported the execution of front-end designs and backend development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, ASP .Net Core MVC, Entity Framework, ADO .Net, and Microsoft SQL Server to ensure a smooth user experience.

Software Developer

NSS Pvt Ltd | November 2023 - Present

- Led cross-functional collaboration to spearhead the development and continuous enhancement of cutting-edge, responsive websites, prioritizing an intuitive user interface and seamless functionality across an array of devices and browsers.
- Assisted in implementing front-end designs and backend development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, ASP .Net Core MVC, Entity Framework, ADO .Net and Microsoft SQL Server, ensuring a seamless user experience.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

EMPLOYEE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

- Application built in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React JS, C#, ASP .Net Core,Entity Framework and Microsoft SQL Server.
- Worked on designs of various forms in the applications.
- Solved common issues in the application to maintain the proper flow.
- Worked on API Development and Integration.
- Connected with Backend.